ILGWU Archives Department Collected Publications 5780/121 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Archives Department Collected Publications
1895-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/121 PUBS
7.5 cubic feet
7.5 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
In addition to documentation of the archives' everyday operation, the papers of ILGWU archivist Robert Lazar include photocopies of materials from the ILGWU records, collected printed material about the ILGWU, sheet music, meeting minutes of local unions, and accounting ledgers.
7461926
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, July 15, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The ILGWU Archives were established in New York City in 1973, under the direction of Henoch Mendelsund. Robert Lazar served as archivist. The archives sought to collect union correspondence, meeting minutes, collective bargaining agreements, publications, photographs, audio recordings, film, and memorabilia. In 1987, the ILGWU Archives were transferred to the Kheel Center.
Scope and Contents
The records of the Archives Department include administrative records files relating to the establishment and operation of the unit, subject files containing photocopies of archival material, archival records maintained by the department, and publications.
Administrative records document how the archive was built, operated, and used. They include inventory and accession forms, correspondence with union officials and donors, financial records, and guidelines for the processing and care of archival records. These also include procedures for using the collections, guidelines for donating materials, and signed forms by researchers who accessed the archives. Materials relating to the archives' oral history project are also contained in these administrative files. These oral history audio recordings and transcripts (5780 OH and 5780/110 OHT) are available at the Kheel Center.
Subject files include prominent figures in the union, local unions, and other ILGWU affiliates and contain photocopies of records documenting the work of these individuals and organizations. Among the subject files and archival records are the ILGWU's founding meeting minutes (5780/111, box 1, folder 13), as well as minutes of the ILGWU predecessor union Sanctuary Local Assembly 3038 of the Knights of Labor.
Archival records include union correspondence, accounting ledgers, local union meeting minutes, and other material. The accounting ledgers of the Central States region are among the relatively few records held at the Kheel Center that document the activities of that department. The meeting minutes of Local 89, Local 48, Local 414, and Local 2585/414 fill out gaps in other series. These records from the Archives Department complement those in other series of the ILGWU Records
The Archives Department Publications (5780/121 PUBS) consist of printed material collected by the unit. They include newsletters and newspapers from local unions, collective bargaining agreements, membership censuses, financial and statistical reports, information welfare funds, legal records, and some material related to arbitration. Included in the papers of longtime ILGWU Archivist Robert Lazar (5780/121) is published sheet music.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/111: ILGWU Archives Department Records 5780/121: ILGWU Archives Department, Robert Lazar Papers
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
7461926
- 80th Anniversary Local 117, ILGWU, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: 80th Anniversary Local 117, ILGWU, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Local 117. Item is in English.
- The 99er, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  v.2:no.8-9 (1945:June/July-Aug./Sept.)
  - Item 1: The 99er, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Local 99. v.2:no.8-9 (1945:June/July-Aug./Sept.). Item is in English.
- The ABC of Trade Unionism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The ABC of Trade Unionism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Education Department. Item is in English.
- Agreements in the Dress Industry, 1936-1939, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Cover embossed: Harry Uviller
  - Item 1: Agreements in the Dress Industry, 1936-1939, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Cover embossed: Harry Uviller. Item is in English.
- Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, 1937-1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Cover embossed: Louis Reiss
  - Item 1: Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Joint Board of Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Reefer Makers' Union. Cover embossed: Louis Reiss. Item is in English.
- Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, 1943-1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, 1948-1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, 1951-1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Joint Board of Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Reefer Makers' Union. Item is in English.
- Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, 1954-1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Agreements of the Joint Board Cloakmakers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Agreements of the Joint Board Cloak, Suit and Allied Garment Makers' Union, 1973-1976; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Cover embossed: Shelley Appleton
  - Item 1: Agreements of the Joint Board Cloat, Suit and Allied Garment Makers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Joint Board Cloat, Suit and Allied Garment Makers' Union. Cover embossed: Shelley Appleton. Item is in English.
- Agreements of the Joint Board Cloak, Suit and Allied Garment Makers' Union, 1976-1979; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Agreements of the Joint Board Cloat, Suit and Allied Garment Makers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Arbitration Proceedings Between the Dress and Waist Manufacturers' Association and Local 25, Waist and Dress Makers' Union, Local 10, Cutters' Union, and the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union., 1914; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  At the Bar Association Rooms, November 6 and 7, 1914
  - Item 1: Arbitration Proceedings Between the Dress and Waist Manufacturers' Association and Local 25, Waist and Dress Makers' Union, Local 10, Cutters' Union, and the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union., Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    At the Bar Association Rooms, November 6 and 7, 1914. Item is in English.
- The Belt maker, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  English and Spanish. v.57:no.7 (1957:July)
  - Item 1: The Beltmaker, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By Local 40. v.57:no.7 (1957:July). Item is in English; Spanish.
- Bulletin, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  3 copies
  - Item 1: Bulletin, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Dressmakers' Joint Council. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Building Tomorrows Labor Leadership, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Reprinted from AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department Digest, Summer 1957. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Building Tomorrows Labor Leadership, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    By Gus Tyler. Reprinted from AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department Digest, Summer 1957. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Catalogue of Interviews: Connecticut Workers and A Half Century of Technological Change, 1930-1980 Oral History Project, 1983; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Catalogue of Interviews: Connecticut Workers and A Half Century of Technological Change, 1930-1980 Oral History Project, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By Michele Palmer; Janet Nolan; Brian O'Connor. Item is in English.
- Census, 1935-1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  June 1, 1935 - May 31, 1936. Published October, 1936. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Auditing Department. June 1, 1935 - May 31, 1936. Published October, 1936. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census, 1947; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  January 1, 1947 - December 31, 1947. Published 1948. 2 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1947 - December 31, 1947. Published 1948. 2 copies. Item is in English.
- Census, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  January 1, 1951 - December 31, 1951. Published March, 1952. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 2 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1951 - December 31, 1951. Published March, 1952. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 2 copies. Item is in English.
- Census, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  January 1, 1953 - December 31, 1953. Published March, 1954. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1953 - December 31, 1953. Published March, 1954. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  January 1, 1954 - December 31, 1954. Published March, 1955. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1954 - December 31, 1954. Published March, 1955. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  January 1, 1955 - December 31, 1955. Published March, 1956. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1955 - December 31, 1955. Published March, 1956. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  January 1, 1958 - December 31, 1958. Published March, 1959. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1958 - December 31, 1958. Published March, 1959. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. Item is in English.
- Census, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  January 1, 1959 - December 31, 1959. Published March, 1960. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1959 - December 31, 1959. Published March, 1960. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
  January 1, 1960 - December 31, 1960. Published March, 1961. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1960 - December 31, 1960. Published March, 1961. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census Report 1962, Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
  January 1, 1962 - December 31, 1962. Published March, 1963. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census Report 1962, Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1962 - December 31, 1962. Published March, 1963. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census Report 1964, 1965; Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Compiled March 1965. 3 copies
  - Item 1: Census Report 1964, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
    By Auditing Department. Compiled March 1965. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Census Report 1967, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  January 1, 1967 - December 31, 1967. Published March, 1968. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Census Report 1967, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    By Auditing Department. January 1, 1967 - December 31, 1967. Published March, 1968. Comparison of dues-paying members with actual census and statistical schedule of dues per capita payments by locals and joint boards to the International. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- The Centenary of Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1882-1982, 1985; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Final report of the New York State FDR Centennial Commission
  - Item 1: The Centenary of Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1882-1982, Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    By New York State FDR Centennial Commission. Final report of the New York State FDR Centennial Commission. Item is in English.
- Cloak Out-of-Town Horizon, 1948-1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  v.1:no.1-6 (1948-1949)
  - Item 1: Cloak Out-of-Town Horizon, Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
    By Joint Council of the Cloak Out-of-Town Deparment. v.1:no.1-6 (1948-1949). Item is in English.
- The Clothing and Textile Industries in New York and Its Environs, 1925; Publication (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Item 1: The Clothing and Textile Industries in New York and Its Environs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 31)
    By B. M. Selekman; Henriette R. Walter; W. J. Couper. Item is in English.
- Commemoration: Fiftieth Anniversary First Union Health Center, 1964; Publication (Box 1, Folder 32)
  June 5-6, 1964. 3 copies.
  - Item 1: Commemoration: Fiftieth Anniversary First Union Health Center, Publication (Box 1, Folder 32)
    By ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union). June 5-6, 1964. 3 copies. Item is in English.
- Conciliation, Arbitration, and Sanitation in the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York City, 1912; Publication (Box 1, Folder 33)
  In Bulletin No.98 of the Bureau of Labor, 1912. 3 copies, two bound together.
  - Item 1: Conciliation, Arbitration, and Sanitation in the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York City, Publication (Box 1, Folder 33)
    By Charles H. Winslow. In Bulletin No.98 of the Bureau of Labor, 1912. 3 copies, two bound together. Item is in English.
- The Conservative Tilt in the Elections, 1962; Publication (Box 1, Folder 34)
  In The American Federationist, v.69:no.10 (1969:Oct.)
  - Item 1: The Conservative Tilt in the Elections, Publication (Box 1, Folder 34)
    By Gus Tyler. In The American Federationist, v.69:no.10 (1969:Oct.). Item is in English.
- Constitution and By-Laws of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1962; Publication (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Revised May, 1962
  - Item 1: Constitution and By-Laws of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 35)
    By ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union). Revised May, 1962. Item is in English.
- Constitution of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1977; Publication (Box 1, Folder 36)
  As adopted by Thirty- Sixth Convention at Hollywood, Florida, May and June, 1977.
  - Item 1: Constitution of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 36)
    By ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union). As adopted by Thirty-Sixth Convention at Hollywood, Florida, May and June, 1977. Item is in English.
- Contrato Colectivo de Trabajo Firmad Entre la Union de Industrials Textiles de Tejidos de Punto y de la Confeccion y el Sindicato Unico de Trabajadores Textiles, Confeccion y sus Similares del Distrito Federal y Estato Miranda (SUTRATEX), Publication (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Spanish
  - Item 1: Contrato Colectivo de Trabajo Firmad Entre la Union de Industriales Textiles de Tejidos de Punto y de la Confeccion y el Sindicato Unico de Trabajadores Textiles, Confeccion y sus Similares del Distrito Federal y Estato Miranda (SUTRATEX), Publication (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Item is in Spanish.
- Corset and Brassiere Workers Bulletin, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 38)
  v.1:no.4 (1958:Sept.)
  - Item 1: Corset and Brassiere Workers Bulletin, Publication (Box 1, Folder 38)
    By Local 32. v.1:no.4 (1958:Sept.). Item is in English.
- Court Versus Legislature, 1962; Publication (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Reprinted from Law and Contemporary Problems; The Electoral Process: Part II, Summer 1962. 2 copies
  - Item 1: Court Versus Legislature, Publication (Box 1, Folder 39)
    By Gus Tyler. Reprinted from Law and Comtemporary Problems; The Electoral Process: Part II, Summer 1962. 2 copies. Item is in English.
- Crime and Delinquency: Organized Crime, 1962; Publication (Box 1, Folder 40)
  v.8:no.4 (1962:Oct.)
  - Item 1: Crime and Delinquency: Organized Crime, Publication (Box 1, Folder 40)
    By Robert F. Kennedy; Gus Tyler; Virgil W. Peterson; Herbert A. Bloch; Edwyn Silberling; Mortimer M. Caplin; Joseph P. Hoey; Milton G. Rector; Sanford Bates; Armine Dikijian. v.8:no.4 (1962:Oct.). Item is in English.
- David Dubinsky and Phillip Kapp v. Blue Dale Dress Co. and Blue Fox Dress Co., Publication (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Plaintiffs' Trial Memorandum
  - Item 1: David Dubinsky and Phillip Kapp v. Blue Dale Dress Co. and Blue Fox Dress Co., Publication (Box 1, Folder 41)
    By Emil Schlesinger; Abraham Schlesinger. Plaintiffs' Trial Memorandum. Item is in English.
- David Dubinsky: A Pictorial Biography, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Foreword by William Green. Introduction by Walter P. Reuther. 2 copies.
  - Item 1: David Dubinsky: A Pictorial Biography, Publication (Box 1, Folder 42)
    By John Dewey; William Green; Walter P. Reuther. Foreword by William Green. Introduction by Walter P. Reuther. 2 copies. Item is in English.
- Death Benefit Fund of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Rules and Regulations, 1965; Publication (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Effective May 18, 1965
  - Item 1: Death Benefit Fund of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Rules and Regulations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 43)
    By Death Benefit Fund Department. Effective May 18, 1965. Item is in English.
- Death Benefit Fund of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Rules and Regulations, 1969; Publication (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Amended to January 1, 1969
  - Item 1: Death Benefit Fund of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Rules and Regulations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 44)
    By Death Benefit Fund Department. Amended to January 1, 1969. Item is in English.
- Decision. New Jersey Court of Errors and Appeals, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Item 1: Decision. New Jersey Court of Errors and Appeals, Publication (Box 1, Folder 45)
    By Abraham J. Isserman. Item is in English.
- Domestic Textile Industry and International Trade, 1977; Publication (Box 1, Folder 46)
  In Congressional Record, v.123:no.152 (1977:Sep. 27). 2 copies.
  - Item 1: Domestic Textile Industry and International Trade, Publication (Box 1, Folder 46)
    In Congressional Record, v.123:no.152 (1977:Sep. 27). 2 copies. Item is in English.
- The Dress Presser, 1947; Publication (Box 1, Folder 47)
  English and Yiddish. February, 1947.
  - Item 1: The Dress Presser, Publication (Box 1, Folder 47)
    By Local 60. February, 1947. Item is in English; Yiddish.
- Dressmakers' Bulletin, 1928-1929; Publication (Box 1, Folder 48)
  English and Yiddish. No.1-[6] (1928- 1929)
  - Item 1: Dressmakers' Bulletin, Publication (Box 1, Folder 48)
    By Joint Board Cloak and Dressmakers' Union. No.1-[6] (1928-1929). Item is in English; Yiddish.
- Dressmakers' Press, 1980; Publication (Box 1, Folder 49)
  v.1:no.2 (1980:Dec.)
  - Item 1: Dressmakers' Press, Publication (Box 1, Folder 49)
    By Local 22. v.1:no.2 (1980:Dec.). Item is in English.
- Education: An Information Tool / L'Education un Outil D 'Information, 1986; Publication (Box 1, Folder 50)
  English and French
  - Item 1: Education: An Information Tool / L'Education un Outil D'Information, Publication (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Item is in English; French.
- The Emancipator, 1938-1945; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The Emancipator, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    By Milwaukee Joint Board. Item is in English.
- Ever In Accord, 1942; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Ever In Accord, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Item is in English.